# Simu Liu

## Full Stack Developer

🔀 simuliu711@gmail.com 💡 Montreal, QC, Canada 🌘 apple0441

#### **Profile**

Full-stack developer with over 7 years' experience, specializing in React and React Native development. He has developed a wide range of applications including diabetes tracking, event booking and ticketing, and budgeting. Simu Liu works in a clear and organized manner, ensuring that projects are well planned before he starts coding. He brings exceptional value in seeing projects through from start to finish, while adding new features to existing products.

## **Professional Experience**

#### Full Stack Developer, Trigent

03/2021 - 05/2023 | Remote

- Built a web application that allowed 75,000 users to search for nearby restaurants based on their location with 89% accuracy.
- Worked with a team of 27 developers to build an e-commerce website in 3 months using PHP, MySQL and JavaScript.
- Developed a responsive email template in HTML5 and CSS3 that increased the click-through rate by 78%, an improvement over previous years.
- Participated in code reviews of 100 developers, ensuring that all code was 100% compliant with coding standards and best practices.

#### **Full Stack Developer,** Webcrafters

02/2018 - 02/2021 | Warszawa, Poland

- Developed a brand new administration panel for purchasing agent business, which increased the customer service by 90% and improved the efficiency of operating by over 25%
- Increased customer satisfaction to 85% by creating database utilizing PDO, and MySQL that streamlined tracking operations from creating, assigning and tracking truckloads.
- Developed 25 original e-commerce website and web applications, encompassing design, coding, testing and maintenance whilst supervising a team of 15 web developers.

#### **Junior Web Developer,** *TapInfluence*

12/2015 - 01/2018

Mountain View, United States

- Created a new landing page system using a PostgreSQL database and s3 bucket to drive the images and links for quick searches on the platform.
- Collaborated on the search platform routing system using react-router so that all searches were URL driven, allowing for saved and quick navigation.
- Built a simple user interface for the data science team to test their new features without using URLs or Postman.
- Extended the internal data science tool into a separate client facing platform for creating smaller, less focused influencer marketing campaigns using React, React-Apollo and GraphQL.
- Learned React and Redux to work on the new search platform concept, the first foray into using React on the platform.

## **Education**

### **Bachelor of Computer Science,**

Hong Kong University of Science and Technology(HKUST) ☑

09/2012 - 11/2015 | Kowloon, Hong Kong

 $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\bullet$ 

## **Skills**

English

MERN MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js	••••	<b>MEAN</b> MongoDB, Express.js, Angular.js, Node.js	• • • •
<b>MEVN</b> MongoDB, Express.js, Vue.js, Node.js	• • • •	<b>Django</b> (HTML, CSS, JS/TS, python)	• • • •
LAMP Linux, Apache, MySQL ,PHP/Python/Perl	••••	<b>Database</b> MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB, NoSQL	• • • •
WordPress	••••	<b>Cloud</b> Firebase, Cloudflare, AWS	••••
Languages			

Chinese